Prejeeth Thirumani UI & UX Design

prejeeththedesigner.com prejeetht@gmail.com 925 482 6690

OBJECTIVE

With over 12 years of experience I am adept at providing UX solutions for complex scenarios. I bring empathy, passion, and commitment to my work. I hope to use and expand these talents at a company that prioritizes the user's experience of a product and recognizes the value of user-centered design.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Visual Communication

Loyola College

Graduation: March 2003

Relevant coursework: Principles of design, elements of design, cognitive psychology, human communication, drawing, media culture and society, graphic design, advertising, research, visual analysis tools, visualizing and illustration, photography.

Master of Arts in Communication Madural Kamaraj University

Graduation: August 2005

Relevant coursework: Design fundamentals, development communication, media research methods, photojournalism and infographics, digital story telling, new social media, adversing and creativity.

KEY WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Designer (contracting) CSAA (AAA) Insurance

May 2012 - Till date

I led interaction design for responsive and complex large-scale websites. Worked in both waterfall and agile methods on a variety of web interfaces including desktop and mobile. Developed relationships with a wide range of stakeholders to design end-to-end experiences using participatory and iterative design techniques.

Senior Designer (contracting) The Toro Company

May 2009 - October 2011

As lead designer i was responsible for delivering intuitive end-to-end strategic user experience and visual design. Responsible for requirement gathering, user flows, storyboards, personas, wireframes, low fidelity mock-ups, hi-fi prototypes UI specifications and front end development.

Visualizer

Dzine Garage, Interactive Digital Lab

August 2004 - February 2006

I was one of the primary user experience and interface design specialists creating usable UI for complex scenarios for a variety of corporate and e-commerce projects.

KEY PROJECTS

UX Designer

CSAA (AAA), Insurance Portal Responsive Design

May 2012 - Till Date - California

I partnered with various product analysts to work through the early stages of the design; working from strategy and feature definition into information architecture, sketching and prototyping, UI designing, testing and iterating. Participated in user research and synthesis through designer lead user research (DLUR) and contextual enquiry. Established collaboration and communication between the design, development, and business leadership teams. I implemented formal design reviews, created best practices around documentation (lean UX) and specification.

UX Designer

Toro, E-Commerce Website Design

May 2009 - October 2011 - Minnesota

I participated in user research, identified opportunities from the research that balanced the needs of the users with the needs of the client, created interactive medium fidelity prototypes, and was responsible for the visual design of the final product mock-ups and also front end development.

UX Designer

FisherPrice, E-Commerce Website Maintenance

April 2008 - October 2008 - New York

I was the lead designer responsible for the localization and maintenance of Fisher-Price.com understanding the business requirements and coordinating deliverables with other user experience designers.

UX SKILLS

Contextual inquiry, competitive analysis, heuristic evaluation, card sorting, persona development, storyboards, A/B testing, DLUR (designer lead user research), clickable protoypes, visual mockups, lean UX, design patterns, styleguide and more!

TOOLS

Adobe Design Suite, Axure, GitHub, Zurb Foundation, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Terminal, Sublime Text, Virtualbox (older IE browser tester)